Virtual reality started for me in sort of an unusual place.
我第一次接触虚拟现实是在一个不大寻常的情况下。
It was the 1970s.
那是十九世纪七十年代，
I got into the field very young: I was seven years old.
我在很小的时候就接触了这个领域：那时候才七岁。
And the tool that I used  to access virtual reality
我用于进入虚拟现实的工具
was the Evel Knievel stunt cycle.
是Evel Knievel特技摩托车模型。
This is a commercial for  that particular item:
在当时它的广告是这样的：
(Video) Voice-over: What a jump!
（录像）旁白：跳的好！
Evel's riding the amazing stunt cycle.
Evel正在表演惊人的摩托车特技。
That gyro-power sends him  over 100 feet at top speed.
陀螺仪的能量将他以最高速送上了100英尺的高度！
Chris Milk: So this was my joy back then.
Chris Milk：这就是我那时候快乐的源泉。
I rode this motorcycle everywhere.
我“骑”着它到处跑。
And I was there with Evel Knievel; we  jumped the Snake River Canyon together.
我和Evel Knievel一起跳过了蛇河峡谷。
I wanted the rocket.
我想要那个火箭。
I never got the rocket, I only got the motorcycle.
我从来没有得到过那个火箭，只有这个摩托车。
I felt so connected to this world.
我感到我和这个世界紧紧相连在一起。
I didn't want to be a storyteller  when I grew up, I wanted to be stuntman.
我不想长大后成为一个讲故事的人，我想成为一个特技表演家。
I was there. Evel Knievel was my friend.
我就在那里，而Evel Knievel是我的朋友。
I had so much empathy for him.
我和他心有灵犀。
But it didn't work out. (Laughter)
但是事实并没有朝我期待的方向发展。（笑）
I went to art school.
我去了一个艺术学校。
I started making music videos.
我开始制作音乐视频。
And this is one of the early music videos that I made:
这是我最早期制作的音乐视频之一：
(Music: "Touch the Sky" by Kanye West)
（音乐：Touch the Sky -- Kanye West)
CM: You may notice  some slight similarities here.
你们也许注意到了一些相似之处。
(Laughter)
（笑）
And I got that rocket.
而且我得到了那个火箭。
(Laughter)
（笑）
So, now I'm a filmmaker, or, the beginning of a filmmaker,
所以，现在我是一个制片人，或者说，新手制片人，
and I started using the tools that are available to me as a filmmaker
我开始使用一些用于制作电影的工具，
to try to tell the most compelling stories that I can to an audience.
向观众展示那些最引人入胜的故事。
And film is this incredible medium that allows us to feel empathy
电影是一种不可思议的媒介，能让我们
for people that are very different than us
和非常不同的人，
and worlds completely  foreign from our own.
不同的世界产生共鸣。
Unfortunately,
不幸的是，
Evel Knievel did not feel the same  empathy for us that we felt for him,
Evel Knievel没有对我们产生像我们对他那样的共鸣，
and he sued us for this video --
他起诉了我们这个视频，
(Laughter) --
（笑）
shortly thereafter.
就在不久以后。
On the upside, the man  that I worshipped as a child,
不过往好的方面想，这个我从小崇拜的男人，
the man that I wanted  to become as an adult,
这个我曾今想长大后变成他的男人，
I was finally able to get his autograph.
我终于拿到了他的签名。
(Applause)
（掌声）
Let's talk about film now.
现在来谈谈电影吧。
Film, it's an incredible medium,
电影，是个不可思议的媒介，
but essentially, it's the same now as it was then.
但是基本上从过去到现在它并没有改变很多。
It's a group of rectangles that are played in a sequence.
它只是一组按顺序播放的长方形。
And we've done incredible things with those rectangles.
但是我们用这些长方形做出过非同凡响的事情。
But I started thinking about,
但是我开始思考，
is there a way that I can use modern and developing technologies
我可不可以用现代不断发展的科技，
to tell stories in different ways
通过不同的方法讲故事，
and tell different kinds of stories
讲述不同的故事，
that maybe I couldn't tell using the traditional tools of filmmaking that we've been using for 100 years?
而这些用我们已经使用了100年的传统的电影制作工具却无法实现？
So I started experimenting,
所以我开始进行试验，
and what I was trying to do was to build the ultimate empathy machine.
我想造出一个能最终实现共鸣的机器。
And here's one of the early experiments:
这是我最初的试验之一：
(Music)
（音乐）
So this is called "The Wilderness Downtown."
这个叫做The Wilderness Downtown。
It was a collaboration with Arcade Fire.
是跟Arcade Fire合作的项目。
It asked you to put in the address where you grew up at the beginning of it.
它一开始让你输入你长大的地方。
It's a website.
它是一个网站。
And out of it starts growing these little boxes with different browser windows.
开始后你会在不同的浏览器中看到这些小盒子。
And you see this teenager  running down a street,
你会看到这个少年在街上跑，
and then you see Google Street View and Google Maps imagery
然后看到谷歌街景和谷歌地图，
and you realize the street he's running down is yours.
你会意识到他沿途经过的街道，正是你成长的地方。
And when he stops in front of a house, he stops in front of your house.
当他停下来的时候，是在你的房子前。
And this was great, and I saw people  having an even deeper emotional reaction
这很棒，我看到人们表现出更剧烈的情感波动，
to this than the things that  I had made in rectangles.
相较于我在长方形框框里创造出来的东西。
And I'm essentially taking  a piece of your history
我基本上是拿出来你的一段过去，
and putting it inside  the framing of the story.
把它放入一个故事当中。
But then I started thinking,
然后我开始思考，
okay, well that's a part of you,
好吧，这是你的一部分，
but how do I put all of you inside of the frame?
但是我怎样才能把你的一切都这样呈现出来呢？
So to do that, I started making art installations.
于是，我开始制作装置艺术。
And this is one called  "The Treachery of Sanctuary."
这个叫做“对神圣的背叛”。
It's a triptych. I'm going to show you the third panel.
它是个三联场景。我要展示一下第三部分。
(Music)
（音乐）
So now I've got you inside of the frame,
所以我把你带入了这个画框，
and I saw people having even more visceral emotional reactions
与之前的作品相比，我看到人们的情感
to this work than the previous one.
受到了更多的触动。
But then I started thinking about frames, and what do they represent?
但然后我开始思考，画框到底意味着什么？
And a frame is just a window.
画框只是一个窗户。
I mean, all the media that we watch -- television, cinema --
我的意思是，我们观看的所有媒介——电视，电影院——
they're these windows into  these other worlds.
它们都是通往另一个世界的窗户。
And I thought, well, great.  I got you in a frame.
我想，好，我让你进入一个框。
But I don't want you in the frame, I don't want you in the window,
但是我不想让你在这个框里面，在窗户里面，
I want you through the window, I want you on the other side,
我想要你穿过这个窗户到另一边去，
in the world, inhabiting the world.
到另一个世界，住到那个世界里去。
So that leads me back to virtual reality.
于是这把我带回到了虚拟现实上。
Let's talk about virtual reality.
下面我们说一下虚拟现实。
Unfortunately,
不幸的是，
talking about virtual reality is like dancing about architecture.
谈论虚拟现实就像对着某个体系跳舞。
And this is actually someone dancing about architecture in virtual reality.
而这个人就是在对着虚拟现实里的构建体系跳舞。
(Laughter)
（笑）
So, it's difficult to explain. Why is it difficult to explain?
这个很难解释。为什么这么说呢？
It's difficult because it's a very  experiential medium.
它很难是因为这个只是一个经验上的媒介。
You feel your way inside of it.
你在里面感受到你自己。
It's a machine, but inside of it,
它是个机器，但是在它里面，
it feels like real life, it feels like truth.
你感觉像在真实的世界中。
And you feel present in the world that you're inside
你感到你存在于这个世界中，
and you feel present with the people that you're inside of it with.
而且你能感受到其他人的存在。
So, I'm going to show you a demo of a virtual reality film:
所以，我要给你们展示一个虚拟现实电影的片段：
a full-screen version of all the information
它是我们在摄录虚拟现实的时候
that we capture when we shoot virtual reality.
获得的全部信息的全屏版本。
So we're shooting in every direction.
所以我们在每个角度都会摄像。
This is a camera system that we built
我们打造的这个摄像系统
that has 3D cameras that look in every direction
能够进行立体拍摄，实现各个方向的效果，
and binaural microphones that face in every direction.
还配备了多方位的麦克风装置。
We take this and we build, basically, a sphere of a world that you inhabit.
我们基本上是打造了你居住的一个球形的世界。
So what I'm going to show you is not a view into the world,
那么我要给你们展示的并不是这个世界的一个视角，
it's basically the whole world stretched into a rectangle.
而是整个被拉成长方形的世界。
So this film is called  "Clouds Over Sidra,"
这个电影叫做"乌云下的西德拉“，
and it was made in conjunction with  our virtual reality company called VRSE
由我们的虚拟现实公司VRSE，
and the United Nations,
和联合国，
and a co-collaborator named Gabo Arora.
以及一个合作者，Gabo Arora联合制作。
And we went to a Syrian refugee camp in Jordan in December
我们在12月份去了位于约旦的一个叙利亚难民营，
and shot the story of a 12-year-old girl there named Sidra.
拍摄了这个叫做西德拉的12岁女孩的故事。
And she and her family fled Syria through the desert into Jordan
她和她的家人从叙利亚逃离，穿过沙漠到达了约旦，
and she's been living in this camp for the last year and a half.
她已经在难民营住了一年半了。
(Video) Sidra: My name is Sidra.
（录像）西德拉：我的名字是西德拉。
I am 12 years old.
我12岁。
I am in the fifth grade.
我上五年级。
I am from Syria, in the Daraa Province, Inkhil City.
我来自叙利亚，德拉省的Inkhil市。
I have lived here in the Zaatari camp in Jordan for the last year and a half.
我住在约旦的Zaatari营已经一年半了。
I have a big family:
我家里有很多人：
three brothers, one is a baby.
三个兄弟，其中一个还是小宝宝。
He cries a lot.
他总是哭。
I asked my father if I cried when  I was a baby and he says I did not.
我问我爸爸当我是小宝宝的时候我会哭吗，他说不会。
I think I was a stronger baby than my brother.
我觉得我是个更坚强的小孩子。
CM: So, when you're inside  of the headset.
CM：事实上，当你从耳机中听到这个的时候，
you're not seeing it like this.
你看到的不是这种景象。
You're looking around through this world.
你其实是在环顾周围的世界。
You'll notice you see full 360 degrees, in all directions.
你会发现你能看到360度全方位的世界。
And when you're sitting there in her room, watching her,
当你坐在她的房间中看着她的时候，
you're not watching it through a television screen,
你不是在透过一个电视屏幕看，
you're not watching it through a window, you're sitting there with her.
也不是透过一个窗户看，你是和她一起坐在那里。
When you look down, you're sitting on the same ground that she's sitting on.
当你往下看的时候，你其实是和她坐在同一个地面上。
And because of that,
正因为这样，
you feel her humanity in a deeper way.
你会更深切地感受到她的人性。
You empathize with her in a deeper way.
你和她在更深层次上产生了共鸣。
And I think that we can change minds with this machine.
我认为我们可以用这种机器来改变人的想法，
And we've already started to try to change a few.
我们正在尝试去进行小小的改变。
So we took this film to the World Economic Forum in Davos in January.
所以我们把这个影片拿到了在一月举行的达沃斯世界经济论坛。
And we showed it to a group of people
我们给一组人展示了这个影片，
whose decisions affect the lives of millions of people.
这些人的决定能够改变百万人的生活。
And these are people  who might not otherwise
这些人也许一辈子都不会
be sitting in a tent  in a refugee camp in Jordan.
坐在约旦的难民营里面。
But in January, one afternoon in Switzerland,
但是在一月，在瑞士的一个下午，
they suddenly all found themselves there.
他们突然发现他们就在那里。
(Applause)
（掌声）
And they were affected by it.
他们被深深地触动了。
So we're going to make more of them.
所以我们打算再接再厉。
We're working with the  United Nations right now
我们正在和联合国合作，
to shoot a whole series of these films.
来录制一个电影系列。
We just finished shooting a story in Liberia.
我们刚刚结束在利比里亚的摄录。
And now, we're going  to shoot a story in India.
现在，我们要去印度。
And we're taking these films,
我们要带着这些影片，
and we're showing them  at the United Nations
在联合国上放映，
to people that work there and people that are visiting there.
给在那里工作或者旅游的人们看。
And we're showing  them to the people that can actually change the lives of the people inside of the films.
我们给可以改变电影主人公生活的那些人展示。
And that's where I think we just start to scratch the surface
我认为我们由此才刚刚开始发掘
of the true power of virtual reality.
虚拟现实的真正力量。
It's not a video game peripheral.
它不是一个游戏周边。
It connects humans to other humans in a profound way
它以一种很深刻的方式连接每个人，
that I've never seen before  in any other form of media.
一种史无前例的方式。
And it can change people's perception of each other.
它可以改变人们对他人的印象。
And that's how I think
这就是我为何相信
virtual reality has the potential to actually change the world.
虚拟现实可以真正改变这个世界。
So, it's a machine,
所以，它是个机器，
but through this machine we become more compassionate,
但是通过这个机器，我们变得更有同情心，
we become more empathetic, and we become more connected.
能和他人产生共鸣，彼此间联系得也更紧密了。
And ultimately, we become more human.
最终，我们会变得更有人性。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（掌声）